Hey TJ, congratulations. Uh, what sorts
of conversations did you have with the
Bills throughout the process leading up
to this pick?
>> First of all, thank you. Um, and we
talked at the Senior Bowl a little bit.
Um, you know, just got to meet the some
of the staff and, you know, we just got
to pick my brain and, you know, how I
learned and, you know, how quickly I can
come along when it comes to plays. Um,
and minimal like that, you know. Um, but
just just to see that call come through,
man, it's a blessing. And, you know,
your boy's excited to get to work.
What do you know about uh Jim Leonard,
the new defensive coordinator here? Any
conversations with him?
>> Uh, no sir, not yet. But man, you know,
for me, I'm just super excited to get to
get up to Buffalo to meet the staff, to
get real comfortable because we're going
we're going to get there and we're going
to have some fun. We're going to work
hard. So,
>> thanks.
>> Hi, TJ. Sal Kapacio here. I am the uh
reporter for WGR radio in Buffalo.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> I see you uh go by TJ, it looks like,
but how do you pronounce your first
name? And I do want to make sure. Do you
prefer to just go by TJ?
>> Yes. So, I prefer TJ, but my first name
is Tamarion.
>> Tamarion. Thank you. Um I see your dad
was in the military. Uh thank you for
his service. Um what branch was he in
and how has that shaped you as a
football player and a person?
>> Thank you. Um my dad was in the army.
Um, and for me, you know, just um, my
dad was always about discipline and and
the way you treat people, you know. So,
at an early age, I was always taught to
treat people with respect. Um, and it
treat and that speaks true volume of
your character, you know, cuz who are
you when nobody else is watching, right?
Um, and, you know, I took that and and
applied it to my life as much as
possible and just, you know, the stories
of, you know, things my dad seen and
went through as being a leader. Um, you
know, those growing pains and I can
relate to it the same way. you know,
leading my football team, my teammates,
um trying to be the best leader
possible. Um just just knowing I can
lean on my dad, knowing he's been
through that in a similar fashion and a
much in a much, you know, rougher area
than I have. Uh so just thankful to have
that support. So,
>> and I also see you're married to another
elite athlete. Um how has that uh shaped
you as a football player?
>> Uh it's amazing, man. Her name is Asia.
Uh man, she's super competitive. She
played volleyball at Clemson. Um she
keeps me on my toes, you know, uh always
trying to make me the best athlete in
the world. uh as much as possible, you
know, because knowing that she could be
an elite athlete any sport she pick up.
Uh you know, you got to be on point
whether you want a date or not, you
know. Um and she's helped me in this
process so much just keeping me uh you
know, right on track and you know, doing
things for me just to really make my
life a lot easier and allow me to go be
the best football player I can. Um so,
man, I just really appreciate her and
for what she's done for me.
>> Congratulations again. We'll see you up
here.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yep.
>> Hi, TJ. John Warl with the Associated
Press. Congratulations.
>> Thank you so much.
>> You're on mute.
>> Hello.
>> Uh seeing the background behind you,
where are you and uh what what made you
chose to, you know, be there?
>> Going to my best friend Carrie's house.
You know, um you know, I met him when I
first got to college and I just thought
he, you know, a regular guy, you know,
he was just normal, a great genuine
dude. Um, and he invited me over to his
house one day. Um, and I I first seen
this room and I was just amazed. You can
check it out. All the Clemson greats in
the background, you know. Um, they all
up here. Um, you know, it's amazing. Um,
just to have him in my circle, man. Uh,
you know, his family's big Bill's family
as well. So, they're super excited about
this pick right here. Uh, so, you know,
definitely, you know, you you guys going
to see him around a lot, too. So,
>> wonderful stuff. Um what do you make of
um making I mean you played you played
uh on the line at Clemson but you know
obviously at your size you know you're
going to be uh they they peg you as an
outside linebacker. What about making
that switch uh um position switch in in
that sense makes it um an advantage or a
challenge?
>> Uh for me you know um I think it's it's
a great you know I'm very versatile. You
know on my tape you see I can drop in
coverage, I can rush the pass or I can
stop the run. Um, so that just makes me
versatile all across the board. Um, and
for me, you know, I think that's very
valuable. Um, you know, I'll be going
into the system and whatever they have
for outside linebacker edge type of
role, I'll be able to do. Um, and it's
on tape. So,
>> good stuff. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Hey TJ, uh, Matt Parino from
Syracuse.com. Congratulations.
>> Thank you so much, y'all.
>> Um, can you take me into the the process
a little bit uh, kind of on the road to
the draft? like how many conversations
you you had with the Bills and um kind
of what whether it was when they called
you tonight or any part of the process,
what they kind of told you their vision
for you in their defense is,
>> you know, um I talked to them briefly at
the uh Senior Bowl. Um and you know,
they loved my take. Um they like the way
I finished, you know, at the end of the
season, you know, starting off for
teamwise was a little rough. Um you
know, we always had great contact. you
know, we have some guys who work in the
building with former ath former Clemson
athletes and you know, just uh having
that great relationship with them early
on my freshman year has been great. Um,
you know, um, you know, and from there,
you know, when I got the call and seen
it said Buffalo New York, man, I was
super excited. Uh, you know, just to to
get up here and work. You know, you guys
have a great culture. Um, you guys work
hard and you guys want to win. So, and
that's all about me. So,
>> you had uh 11 sacks in in 2024. real
breakout season this this past season
with five sacks. Obviously, you know,
sacks are hard to get. What went into
maybe that this season as opposed to
kind of the success you had just getting
to the quarterback uh two years ago?
>> Um honestly, you know, I think I I had a
I had a good year, you know. Um I feel
like a lot of stuff on tape I've
improved from my sophomore year to my
junior year. Now, I didn't have the same
amount of uh sack production. Um you
know, but at the same time, you know, I
put great things on tape. You know, I I
give credit to guys on my along amongst
my team. Jahem Lawson, uh Will Help, uh
Kate Denhoff, those guys made a lot more
plays. They stepped up and they helped
out this defense a lot. Um so, credit
goes to them as well. Um you know, so
yeah, we put together a good season.
>> What do you know about Buffalo?
>> I know one thing, the fans love football
and that's one thing I love. You know, I
love a good a organization with a great
culture. Um you know, they're going to
show up for us through the ups and
downs. So, I'm excited to get up there
and meet everybody.
>> Thanks again, TJ. Congrats.
>> Thank you.
>> TJ Parker Hawkins. Congratulations from
Buffalo.
>> Thank you.
>> How would you how would you describe
your games to Bills fans who are just
getting to know you?
>> Uh very physical player who loved to use
his hands. Uh doesn't shy away from
contact in the run or pass game. Very
powerful. um with my long arm and my
speed to power. Um we want a guy who can
change it up and use a little speed. Uh
you know, a guy who's going to try to
play with attitude, run to the ball, get
there fast as possible and put pain on
somebody. You know, we playing fast
physical football this way. Um and I'm
I'm trying to bring the nasty to the
defense. So excited to get up there and
meet my teammates. So,
>> exactly, man. So, uh what really excites
you uh the most about joining this Bills
defense,
>> man. really just to learn from the vets
and the older guys, you know, who've
done it. You know, just get around the
team and and be the best version of me
possible just so I can help this team
win games.
>> What do you think you can make the
quickest impact here at the next level?
>> Uh I think I could be a great teammate.
You know, um football stuff is going to
handle itself. Um you know, and I got a
lot to learn. You know, I'll be having a
great transition uh during Brookie Mini
camping and OTAAS. You know, I'm excited
to to get around the guys and learn from
them and improve my game, you know. um
and also just be a great teammate to
boost up the locker room. So,